GITI SHARMA

Hardworking college graduate with a Masters of Science in Geoinformatics, started working in the domain of GIS. Aiming to leverage work experience and academic knowledge of Geospatial and Location Analysis to successfully build the career ahead.

CONTACT



+91-8586058879



gitisharma22@gmail.com



<u>linkedin.com/in/giti-shar</u> ma-58862817b/



Gurugram, HR

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Geoinformatics

TERI School Of Advanced Studies, Delhi CGPA - 7.88 2018-20

B.A. Geography Honours

University Of Delhi CGPA - 6.946 2015-18

Class 12th

Navy Children School, Chanakyapuri, New Delhi Percentage - 90%

Class 10th

Navy Children School -Chanakyapuri, New Delhi CGPA - 9.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

OGIS

ArcGIS Suite

ERDAS Imagine

Global Mapper & Pix4D

R & Google Earth Engine

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIS Analyst

Sociometrik, New Delhi 2020 - Now

Focus on analyzing spatial data through mapping software and designing digital maps with geographic data.

- Developed maps based on specific attributes using offline/online GIS softwares like QGIS. ArcGIS and others.
- Gathered learning about transforming data into actionable insights which can be utilised to design solutions to enable sustainable growth
- Statistically analyzed data for a research project on location intelligence for real estate in Gautam Budh Nagar, UP.

Summer Intern

GeoEPC Management Advisors Pvt Ltd, Gurugram May 2019 - July 2019

Research Project: UAV (Drone) based survey for high scale precision mapping for a proposed township of Maharashtra.

- Prepared geospatial ready data for the site alongside Samruddhi Expressway, Maharashtra
- Focussed upon developing recce of the site, marking of ground control points, processing the raw images, digitizing the features (trees, buildings, etc) present in the area.
- Ensured adequate measures for quality-checks during the project process.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Atmosphere Project (2019) - The main aim was to find the impact of population on fog holes and to assess the relation between urban heat islands, SO2 pollution and fog holes in the Indo-Gangetic Plains.

Results – areas with 1/2 to 3 million population, tend to produce larger no. of fog holes but are small in area. As the areas are rapidly urbanising it is converting to urban heat islands. It was also seen that fog holes predominantly occurred over areas with high land-surface temp. and majorly over areas where there were major thermal power plants with SO2 emissions.

Water Project (2019) - The main aim was identifying and monitoring the changes of Gangotri Glacier for 2009-2018. To identify snow cover areas for ablation and accumulation period and to monitor the movement of snout over the years.

Results - snout has receded a over 275 sq m in the past decade.